do you know guy it's been over 6 months
since our last podcast that we've
recorded 6 months six months do you
think we will be rusty or do you think
this is going to be fresh and and good
we will have uh internalized everything
had time to think about it uh and then
not be able to articulate that at all no
I re you're right right right should we
start let's get going you're listening
to the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla
on today's episode we're talking about
AI native software development what it
means why it's important and how it will
change the way we create software today
also we introduced ker Jan's new company
his Ambitions vision and plans for the
future my name is Simon Maple I'm the
host of uh this episode as well as the
show and joining me is Guy Pani also a
host for this show Welcome guy uh thank
you Simon hello everyone we've got a
brand new podcast the AI native Dev uh
let's talk a little bit about our
backgrounds first guy because of course
this isn't our first podcast that we've
we've ever done right tell us a little
bit about your previous yeah this is not
the first podcast that we've run the
previous one is called the secure
developer all name resemblance is
coincidental and it was all around how
do we embed security into software
development I started it uh eight years
ago now or something like that and over
100 plus episodes had a chance to talk
to some brilliant people in the security
industry thought leaders in the dev
space really a great experience and it's
still going strong with Daniel and as
the host and at some point in time when
you joined me in there as as a co-host
eight years seems crazy I I did a few
years nowhere near as much as eight
years but we had some good fun on that
we did a lot of the monthly roundups I I
interviewed a number of guests on that
as well but yeah very interesting
podcast also shaping the movement of
security into the developer motion and
onto pass is new here we're talking
about AI native development let's let's
actually Define a little bit about what
that means cuz we don't want to we don't
want to start off with a buzzword that
that is meaningless and gets overloaded
when we don't actually Define it at its
roote what would you say is or what
would you say first of all the need for
AI native software development is yeah I
think to get a little bit philosophical
or historian maybe here I think with
every new development Paradigm really
with every new technology that comes
along the first thing we do is we try to
use that technology to improve the way
we do things today and probably like a
recent example of that is cloud right
Cloud came along you can and continue to
run the vmss that you want but you can
do them on someone else's environment
and that means you don't need to
provision stuff you don't need to manage
your capacity you have a lot of those
you can just make an API call and get
the equivalent of your VM in someone
else's Data Center and so that was a
great opportunity to lift and shift and
get a bunch of boosts out of it and over
time of course we've learned to
appreciate that the True Value the true
opportunity in the cloud is not in the
lift and shift which today we think of
as almost uh negatively or a little bit
as we say it in with the detrimental
tone but rather in Cloud native software
development we understand that if you
were to really change the way you build
software and embrace microservices and
elasticity in your sort of
infrastructure and a variety of other
practices and devops really that evolved
then you can really squeeze the most out
of it and we call this Cloud native
software development and it's harder to
do it right we have the whole world of
digital transformation which is not
entirely about Cloud but it is a painful
process because you have to change how
you do things yeah and so I think with
AI if you look at what's happening today
I think we're doing the same thing again
and so there is what I think of as AI
assisted software development and that
is uh using these like amazing tools
like co-pilot and test Generations we're
going to cover a bunch of those here on
the podcast uh and to boost the way you
develop software today and the reason
they're getting such adoption today the
reason they're so compelling is that
they work within the system but at the
same time we have the belief the
conviction that it is a good path but
it's not the best path that the real
opportunity for developing software in
the era of AI is to think about AI
native software development what is the
software development process that you
would want to have if you were to think
about it from first principles and
really build the whole
methodology assuming expecting Ai and
llms and all the power that they bring
to be to be available and so if we were
to position it then with tools and
solutions that already exist today
obviously one of the big developer AI
tools that that kind of blew a lot of
people away is GitHub co-pilot another
one very recently that was introduced
labeled the a the the AI software
engineer Devin how would you say you
know AI how would you say these tools
play in the space of AI native software
engineering or software development yeah
I think first of all they're amazing
tools right and I I highly recommend in
fact I think it's critical for people to
explore them and to use them were
relevant they're not without their flaws
whether sometimes it's like security
issues with them sometimes it is
hallucinations but I think they are
absolutely a
better way at least over the long hole
to develop software and and they
supercharge and there's a reason so many
developers fall in love with them I
think of let's maybe separate the two so
co-pilot and coding assistant and a
bunch of other tools I think a lot of
them are really in the realm to me of AI
assisted software development and if if
you think about the the requirements to
be able to embrace those tools the
threshold is really quite low right
you're already writing code so there's
no change in how you work and when you
get code completion or Auto autoc
completion of any sort then you can
eyeball it and you can see it's correct
so it's low friction low change for you
and so really all it does it makes you
faster and so that's great and so I I am
entirely in favor of those tools and I
think people should embrace them but I
think at the end of the day that's it's
just selling short the eventual
opportunity of what a I can do these are
assistants they're not autonomous which
we can get to in a sec but also again
you're still working there in in the
same methodology and the same path and I
think I think when we think about AI
native software development we're
thinking more about did you even need to
write that code in the first place could
you how did the Insight that co-pilot
had maybe to choose to introduce that
piece of code to you like that piece has
never been communicated right what if
you talk to that higher level language
to say this is the intent of what I'm
talking about and therefore have the
system create those and once you really
level that up and we can dig into more
like what is the the whole like if you
were to develop software in that fashion
what does that mean in in how you spild
software how you version software and so
I think co-pilot is the right tool for
you to be using today or like coding
system and co-pilot tab n uh augment
coding there's a million of them not a
million but a bunch of them uh and and I
think you should be exploring the ones
that you want to that are right for you
but essentially but it's just it's just
assisted it's they're giving you value
today I'm still in my IDE I'm still
writing line by line I'm Rie doing what
it does every single line and I'm doing
things the same way just hopefully
faster or without having to refer to
documentation and things like that
because it's providing me what it thinks
it needs yeah I think like sometimes
when you when you level it up and you
think of creating with AI then it really
works in these one of these two modes
either the human is in control is in the
driver seat and the AI is the assistant
or and maybe this is the case in the
Devon case the AI is the Creator and the
human is the editor yes uh and I think
when you talk to to most devel velers
and most creators really they didn't
choose to be editors some people love
being editors but maybe many don't
really and so the assistant part is
capping is naturally putting a ceiling
in terms of how much it would help like
you still need to be there maybe if you
want to be a manager on the other side
maybe if you want to be an editor but I
think there's an opportunity to think
about how do you create with AI how do
you separate the pieces that you want to
come from the human and the pieces that
you want to come from the machine and so
I think I think that's often times the
with with creating with AI and and
there's a lot more to be said about that
but specifically for software and for
software development uh a lot of it
comes down to the separation of the sort
of intent from implementation yeah and
what's more fun do you think you
mentioned a couple there yeah what what
from a developer what gets a developer
up in the morning I've done many years
of development where I've actually
really enjoyed you know writing code
designing code I get my aha moments from
a developer's point of view a
developer's role in the future where
where's the excitement going to be for a
developer rather than just writing a
short prompt to Deon or something like
that what's going to get them creative
and and and going in the future I think
I think it's a good question and I think
it's part of the exploration here as we
look to to to figure out what AI native
development is and what is an AI native
developer but I think really the drive
or the two drives that that make softare
development fun one is the sense of
creation you're coming in you want a
thing done and you're getting it done
and I think that's very powerful it's
definitely what motivates me as a
developer and I'm a rusty developer at
this point rust developer or Rusty
develop a rusty yeah or dare I say or
dare I say is there a
difference I suspect so I I don't know I
don't know how well can I read rust I
was a poly Glo developer at some point
in my history before I became overhead
but but I think I think the sense of
creation is a big deal creating I don't
know when you create software we were
just talking at Tes you doing a bunch of
stuff on the marketing front in
Automation and despite the show
affection you had for python you were
building it I think the excitement was
from like look I've created this right
above and beyond whatever sort of
practice you're doing and so I think
that part is something that is critical
for us to preserve when you're creating
you have to sense that you're creating
and that's the problem indeed on of the
editor if you're an editor it feels like
it doesn't feel like it's yours I think
the second part that's interesting in in
software development is the is the kind
of the game like mechanics on it when
you're developing software you can
always level up you're you're solving a
puzzle there's a problem you're writing
code and you you solve that problem and
then you can do that again at different
levels and you can always level up and I
think that's exciting and it has even a
bit of an addictive element to it it
also explains why for instance if you're
an experienced developer you don't get
as much excitement or you're not as
happy to do things again that you've
already done 100 of these rback setups
or a bunch of these login forms and so
that doesn't get you excited because
it's like playing a video game when
you're already at level 100 and you're
being asked to do level five once more
um yeah and and on that as well it's
probably a bunch of other things within
the scope not just coding but the scope
of software development with which
actually when we think about creating a
a good whole app or project things like
whether it's documentation or testing
and all these other areas that
developers tend to put off whether it's
through repetition or just not wanting
to do them there are areas here that
that AI can actually take some of those
bits that a developer isn't as
interesting Will finds least fun take it
away and actually allow them to have
more time doing these other things as
well yeah absolutely I think creation is
about the for but the job of software
development really is probably for most
people maybe 5 10 20% coding yeah and
all the rest of the time is everything
around it now some of that is still
creation it's whatever like ironing out
the sort of the quirks it's testing it's
making sure that it works but a lot of
time it's indeed toil it's indeed
repetition it's updating the
documentation to do to say what you've
actually modified versus NE to doing
twice and a bunch of these things are
things that can be automated so the way
we're talking about it is is very much
talking about the new role of software
development presumably you're thinking
absolutely software development from a a
career or role a job is absolutely
needed going forward despite the
advancements in AI is that right I
absolutely believe software development
is here to stay I think coding is a
different question and I think it's
Again part of that exploration I I think
what is software development software
development is bringing ideas to life in
the digital world it's around creating
something that is either a repetitive
task or it is aggregating information
and activity that happens around or it
is a creative Outlet or just fun and all
of these things like there's no reason
to think that any of them go away so we
would still need to produce software I
think interesting things will happen to
the software development world for
instance when you think about music you
think about the democratization of
creating music it became easier and
easier over time to produce music to
create music and as a result of that
that Chang the music industry it brought
a lot of new creators into the fold a
lot more people can create music which
is amazing it also created a challenge
when it comes to finding the music that
you want it created a discovery
challenge it challenged a bunch of
business models and so things changed
substantially and so I think software
development the need and ability to
create tools for the digital world that
would be alive and well I think core
principles of software development like
the fact that a piece of software
doesn't just get created and thrown away
but rather you want to evolve it you
want to change it you want to modify it
over time things like some pieces of
software being more fun and disposable
while other pieces of software being
very Mission critical and attention to
detail becomes very critical like all of
these properties I think will be very
much the same but I think other
attributes like how do you build
software how do you maintain software
how do you collaborate around software I
think those will
change we have the advantage of only
changing them for the better in terms of
the ecosystem as a whole but it does
imply that some roles and some needs
will need to modify and I think what
we're trying to do here is we're trying
to help Define what that new world is
help preserve the goodness help tap into
into the new power that that we can
provide and also help all of us really
uh adapt to this sort of new reality
learn the relevant skills discard some
bad habits Etc and that's a lot of what
we're going to do in this podcast as
well right we're going to we're going to
we're going to uncover the areas of the
AI environment the AI industry around
software development and we're going to
talk to a ton of Industry experts around
each of these specific uh categories
within the AI tools AI development which
we'll talk about in in a little bit
first of all why don't you just as a
first episode of the podcast tell us a
little bit about your background guy
sure so my background goes basically
from being early in the appsec industry
kind of building tools for application
security before it was known through a
bunch of Acquisitions went on to leave
that and found a company in the devops
space called Blaze looking to make
websites faster and getting acquired by
akami where I was CTO for a bunch of
years and during that period really
learned to appreciate the sort of modern
development and the changes and how do
you need to tune the tools of the craft
say developer tools to the practices and
how they're built out post Akamai which
was a great sort of bunch of years and I
moved to London in the process I I left
and I founded teque which I'm probably
most well known for at the moment in
which we indeed sought to help embed
security into software development on
the premise that developers and
development are moving faster and faster
that will continue that's a good thing
we love that however security would just
not be able to keep up and so you have
to build security into software
development and we believe that you can
achieve that by building a developer
tooling company not a security company
sneak is really my pride and joy has
gone very well a journey with its own
ups and downs always always amazing but
it's done well it's a thousand plus
person company right now a growing
company that hopefully uh continues to
be a generational company and as the
company scaled and grew I got lured uh
back into an entrepreneurial journey and
at the beginning of this year made the
leap to found another company tessel
which we'll talk about over here and I
think there's a lot of learnings from
those Journeys on it we're not going to
belabor you too much with those maybe
except for comparisons to the AI native
world but I think probably the biggest
sense that I got out of it is that if
you seek out if you try to understand
where the world is going and you try to
help push the areas that you think are
correct then you can actually help shape
how things are done you don't do it
alone you do it with amazing thought
leaders and early adopters around that
make it work but you can help everybody
create like a a platform for people to
voice their opinions you can help
synthesize those you can help voice and
add your own and I think a key part of
that was um was building a platform for
sharing those ideas building build a
place for those that are at the
Forefront to be able to share their
learnings share their mistakes with
others I think that was massive in
devops I think that was massive in
developer security and it's a core part
of what we're trying to do here on this
podcast when it comes to AI native
development amazing my my background is
actually as far we we have technical
royalty with us here in terms of the
industry but my my background's been
very much more in the pure software
development for over a decade really at
IBM doing middleware development I moved
more into Devol space after that and I
joined zero turnaround did about six
years there many of you may have heard
from the Java side of a tool called
jrebel which has the I built up the dev
team there and then of course we met um
in the sneak day so you were you were
already a Java champion at the time I'm
not a champion I don't know what you're
talking about I don't have that Prince
compared to a Founder but yeah yeah I
joined sneak of course I had had six
great years at sneak and yeah I myself
actually was doing a similar thing
wanted to join a new stup and of course
then I heard about Tesla and yeah the
rest is history but let's go back to AI
native software development as a
developer in that in in that future that
you just described let's talk about the
pillars of what AI native software
development actually actually means what
what does it stand for what are the core
things that when you look at something
you say yeah this is AI native software
development in practice because it is
doing this thing have you got a A list
or a few that you can share with us yeah
and I think first of all I would start
by saying we don't know yeah and it is a
future there's also a gap between the
sort of expectation of destination and
where we are today right if you tried to
build a service mesh with elastic
Computing and microservices in the very
first days of the cloud you would
probably fail so there's an element of
the maturity of the technology and the
maturity of the practice and it goes
handin hand so some of the stuff is
visionary and some of it is things that
can be applied today and there's
definitely a lot of trying to predict
and forecast and a key part of why we're
having this conversation why we're
hosting this podcast is to as a
community as a group talk about these
principles talk about ideas and I'm sure
whatever it is that I think I know today
will change over the course of the
coming kind of months and years with
that said clearly we have some
hypothesis I think the biggest change
that we should expect that I feel I feel
fairly convinced will happen is the move
from code Centric to spec Centric
development um when you think about how
you develop software today uh you write
you get some requirements you write some
code you make 100 decisions in that code
that never leave the code uh and the
code very quickly becomes the source of
Truth uh and we focus on evolving it and
growing it um and the code couples what
needs to be done and how to do it and
and because of that again like it it all
creates the sort of center of gravity
and orientation I think in the world of
AI native development we will have a
means of specifying what it is that we
need and AI will provide the
implementation and that's a very
different reality first of all it's not
easy like how do you specify software
how do you give the
instructions that that you want how do
you express what it is that you intend
to do how do you scrutinize the
decisions that the AI has done how do
you choose when to delegate when to
explicitly specify Thing versus when to
delegate and so there's a lot to evolve
around it but I think fundamentally you
will specify what it is that you want
and AI will handle the implementation
and because AI handles the
implementation all sorts of interesting
things will happen first of all of
course implementations will become easy
and cheap to implement so this is Keen
to elastic compute what happens when you
can generate an implementation on the
fly secondly like once once you
implement on the fly like that it
becomes language agnostic and that's
interesting okay I built a piece of
software here and it can be in
JavaScript or in python or in Java or in
rust or in any of these languages kind
of right away so what does that do to
software ecosystems how do we think
about that where is it useful where is
it not useful and I think when you think
about software development that's also
interesting okay like how do you what is
this thing the sort of spec that you've
created is that a higher level
programming language is this basically
now the sour code that you're compiling
and if so what is a compiler is there
one compiler are there multiple
compilers how is there one spec language
or the multiple spec languages and then
what's the right way to think about if
if software is so easy to create what's
the right way to think about versioning
that or packaging that if you consider
the difference between VMS or like
physical machines that you host within a
rack in the data center versus how do
you treat managing the elastic machines
that you just spin out and down in in a
cloud environment those are managed very
differently those you manage their life
cycle you manage their sort of identity
their security poster like all of these
things you manage them very differently
and so I think a lot of those types of
questions will come up from this sort of
core change of moving from code Centric
to spec Centric development yeah and I
think that's going to be one of the
biggest kind of challenges for the new
age of software development where
developers who are very familiar with
writing code and and hopefully living as
much time as they can in the IDE to
effectively understanding okay how can I
actually address this problem through
natural language understanding the
higher level Concepts versus the lower
level lines of code that they actually
need to create so it up levels
developers in in their thought process
as to what's important for the
application versus just the specifics of
the implementation so and I think like
the first time we talked about this idea
then I think you said that this will
turn developers into Architects yeah
which I think I like that analogy like
it is a higher level thought maybe some
will take the route of architect this is
how I want to describe the system so I
might go more the route of the product
manager and maybe there's sort of other
types of titles or responsibilities that
we can't quite think of yet um but your
ability to articulate what you want and
your ability to articulate your taste
your preferences the trade-off that you
want to make and of course the ability
of whatever sort of system is there to
help get those out of you and and
capture that all of those will control
how good the result would be yeah
there's the potential there as well for
us to because we're because we're
thinking about it at that level we're
thinking about it as the business value
the the use cases that we're trying to
address rather than getting lost in the
code it gives the potential for building
better applications because we're not
we're not focused on the implementation
we're focused on the use cases and the
higher level functional and
non-functional aspects of the
application that we're trying to build
apparently this this podcast is hosted
by a company called tessel now I've I've
I've I've heard of some companies that
like to emit vowels Tesla is one of them
um have you heard of them before I
Googled them before we started and I you
there wasn't much there couldn't find it
no I couldn't I couldn't see that much
it's a condition I
have drop the vowels on the uh then and
the sort of irresistible drive for for
brevity in the names so yeah t it's a
bit better because sneak had no vowels
so at least we've gone from this is the
zero to one it's it's an evolution it's
progress right every every company you
get a little bit better yeah so tesel is
the new company I founded earlier this
year it indeed focuses priz on AI native
software development our goal and I say
our here because Simon you're helping
build this Dev movement here and this
motion and change alongside the company
our goal really is on one hand as we're
doing here in this podcast is help
promote this idea of AI native software
development help shape this with the
community help prepare our all into this
next generation of software development
and build a platform that enables that
to build a platform that is a sort of
built for AI native software development
across its life cycle there's a lot of
unknowns over there we're still figuring
it out as we're doing it uh and that's
the fun in it yeah amazing and today of
course as this podcast the day this
episode is aired it's the launch of
tessle website tessle Blog tessle the
podcast of course as well so an exciting
time for tesle what can people expect
going forward yeah it it is super
exciting to be out there and I think
this is this is very much a mission that
is anchored in the future right we're
thinking about where is the world going
we're looking to evolve it with the
system and so I think what you can
expect from us is just a lot of
collaboration a lot of conversation and
decent amount of experimentation on it
we hope and hopefully even this year to
launch some products that you can try in
beta form you can give us the opinion on
you can work with us to again reshape
and figure out what is correct get a
little bit of mileage of what actually
works with today's technology what
doesn't get that feedback to whomever it
is that needs it and adapt ourselves
accordingly and so I think in the
meantime what you will see from us is
really a lot of this we're going to
publish content we'll talk to smart
people and help give stage to their
thoughts we'll talk to you know AI tools
that you can actually use today so a lot
of the things that we expect to do in
this podcast and you'll see on our blog
you'll see in our newsletter is just
really boosting the conversation around
this domain and in the background we're
working on trying to build a a product
platform that learns from those and that
helps both fulfill some of these
promises but also try out some of these
ideas and see what works absolutely and
I think one thing I will say of course
is this is a a journey of collaboration
you're more than welcome to go to the
Tesla website where we do have the blog
on and podcast do sign up there as well
and you'll hear not just about the great
content that we're pushing out ourselves
with others in the industry but yeah as
and when those these new products become
available and open for early stage
testing we'll absolutely let everyone
know and hopefully get you on board as
early as possible for your feedback and
to see what the next Jour of software
development hopefully looks like now we
drew the comparison actually with sneak
a little bit earlier and how sneak was
really there to address the change in
the movement of bringing security into
the into that developer fold how would
you say how would you draw that parallel
with
doing something
similar I think
sneak gave me the conviction that if
something is the right motion then if
you really explore how to make it happen
it can become reality and so when I
started sneak a lot of the push back was
developers don't care about security
they will never Embrace security and
there was really no nobody arguing with
me that they must and so there was this
oxymoron of on one hand saying yes we
agree devops Cloud all of these
technologies have accelerated software
development there's no way security can
keep up they're already falling behind
we don't see another way it has to get
in developers but developers will never
Embrace security they're there all sorts
of like cynical comments of you know
they only care about their sort of
feature function and things like that
and I think the the sort of a cynicism
isn't very helpful what we've done at
Nick is well actually well if it must
happen how do we do it and we really
embarked on that and say okay if we only
cared about getting developers to
embrace security what would we do and
that's the path we pursued and I feel
like we've been successful we're far
from perfect developers have not like
gener security as they sort of top of
the list but I think we've managed to
Pioneer approaches to how to get
developers to to make security a natural
part of their daily flow you now see
most Dev tools introduce some element of
security into them and you've seen
pretty much all security teams Embrace
this as part of their security program
and I think if you stick to the trend
line if you stick to the destination of
things that must happen then you can Zig
and zag but it's not like we we got it
all right but you can actually there
there's real opportunity to help find
that path and when you do once you open
that door you get to shape the industry
like you get to to modify or help unlock
a certain practice and so I think that
was very uplifting and above and beyond
whatever the success of the business of
it it really felt like we met manag to
to put this slice of the industry on the
right path I think our ambition here is
bigger it's not the developer security
is small by any stretch of imagination
but I think here we're talking about
something a bit more a bit more massive
and I think part of our challenge is to
think about how do we narrow this down
how do we bring it down to reality how
do we make it work today so we start
learning because like everything
everything is a product and V1 always
sucks and so so you have to get started
and I think the kind of the maybe the
tactics that are quite critical to to
making that happen is first and foremost
find your allies figure out who is also
on the sort of bandwagon of AI native
software development get their thoughts
try things out we're keen like what
we're building is very Broad and so
because of that we can't ship it quite
as quickly as we ship snake but we're
keen to put it in the wild to get the
feedback to be told when we're being
idiots but I think you have to work
through iteration you're not going to
get it right and then to stay true to
the conviction and so my conviction in
tessle I think our conviction as a
company is that AI native software
development will happen that AI is too
dramatic the ability for a machine to
generate code is so powerful that
there's no way that the correct way to
develop software is the same as it was
today and basically if that premise
remains correct then I think there's
value to be had here and there's
valuable kind of product and solutions
to be created yeah when you say it's I I
love the words it's it's a bit massive
it's a little bit
massive there there is everyone's
mileage varies today with AI when we
think about this such a large jump is is
this just a fantasy in terms of where
the future versus the actual technology
that we have today is this is it like
you said a couple of times
hallucinations llms making things up are
we where we need to be right now how do
we get to that stage where we can trust
AI enough to actually be comfortable in
this land of on software development
yeah I think it's a very good question
and I think practically every core
technology that we use today and
Technology advancement was perceived as
a fantasy at one point in time I think
it's less of a fantasy than some things
whatever flying cars it's not a sci-fi
movie I do think it stretches the
boundaries and in general like llms are
uh are limited today if you talk to
anybody that is building llms they talk
about how they're so weak still today
because they see all of that potential
but I guess we're building tessel and
we're building this or trying to develop
this notion of ative development in a
way that is anchored in the future and
so the bet we're making is that these
models do become orders of magnitude
better that our ability to Wrangle them
really improves as well so fine there's
the ability to generate code but not
everything has to be AI not everything
AI has to be llms and so these are tools
that we can create and yes it's on us to
try and and find the narrower Paths of
maybe slightly simpler software or more
achievable solutions that we can build
in the short term but fundamentally I
guess we're building the company with an
eye to the Future and so the criticality
isn't about how quickly AI native
development comes about and more about
what's the best way to get it right what
is it that we can do to learn and I
guess we have the the advantage with the
sort of the background of the team of
having a a little bit more string a
little bit more rope to take a bit of
time to develop that so we want to
develop it with everybody here we want
to ship things so we're told that they
that they're wrong so we know which
paths to take we want to try things and
see if we can make them work I my
expectation I don't know if it's
prediction but at least what I think is
good for plan a is that the rate of
progression for these kind of llms and
specifically code generation within them
would be
very fast it something that people don't
think about too much is code like a
small number of other domains it is
veriable and so when you think about how
much can you battle hallucinations and
things like that the more kind of
elusive the domain is and it's hard to
tell whether our result is correct or
not and mass the harder it is to get rid
of hallucinations but code is actually a
place in which oftentimes you can get
deterministic results and as a result of
that is actually Pro maybe the or
definitely one of the fastest
progressing domains within the llms
there are also some dedicated
foundational models that focus on code
only and so I think there's a lot to be
that that is coming quickly yeah amazing
and I think when we think about the the
structure of this podcast we're going to
be going forward doing like two I guess
we we're trying to we're trying to do
two paths here one which is the today
looking forward we have this vision of
what the future could look like but we
equally have these tools here today and
how can we improve our existing software
development practices today every week
on a Tuesday I'm going to be releasing a
new podcast episode which is going to be
looking at the tools of today whether
it's development through code completion
whether it's testing or documentation or
whatever it's going to be and we're
going to we're going to be talking with
a number of different people to really
understand what we can do today with
their tooling why and how AI improves
that aspect of software development and
what they see are their next steps in
this AI Journey going forward you're
doing a little bit different of course
you're starting out like you say
anchoring in that future who are the
types of people you're going to be
talking to sometimes it's the same
people that you might be talking to or
people from the same companies that are
just trying to think further ahead out
there and I think many of the
conversations that that you'll be having
talk about today but a lot of the
technology and practices that are being
built in this AI assisted path are
actually critical learnings to be able
to figure out the destination I think
some of the best companies in the sort
of the a to space they don't just think
about the thing they'll develop today
and how do they whatever beat the
competition but they also think about
what is the destination how does that
work in five years time what do they
imagine and oftentimes they will have
unique insights about that domain I'll
also try to get a bunch of people that
come from different worlds of Creation
with AI of building AI tools and try to
kind of capitalize and leverage their
learnings about where the world of AI
native other things is going because
because I think in many of these cases
those things apply back to the world of
development and we want to be inspired
from outside the industry as well and I
think the combined views of of the today
and the tomorrow should help us try to
draw a line to how we get from a reality
today which already sometimes feels like
science fiction in its own way right go
off and and chat to one of these LMS to
to the sort of I guess further future
yeah it does feel like science fiction
actually cuz me writing python who would
ever have guessed that right
uh but that's is that dystopian or
utopian I don't know knows who knows
could be either so yeah one of the
interesting things as well is that we're
not here to we're not here to talk
Solutions we're really here to ask the
questions and learn as a community so we
want to like really understand what the
right questions are to be asking the
right people and try and understand this
new world as a group and as a community
I think the value of getting these
opinions from the different people
really cannot be understated we're deep
in this domain we think we'll have some
things to share we'll have our own
learning earnings but really and again
this is maybe a learning from the
developer security Journey the True
Value comes from talking to many others
that have used AI Dev tools that have
built AI Dev tools that thought about
where they're going to that that are
actually trying a bunch of these paths
and in those conversations sometimes you
get nuggets of wisdom of hey this is an
entirely new idea that you didn't get
and those are very valuable sometimes
you get affirmations for things you
already know and sometimes you get
pattern matching you get okay everybody
is doing this okay there's something
there that we have to understand so like
with anything data there's elements of
quality you're going to get these sort
of moments of brilliant from Brilliance
from these amazing people around and
there's going to be uh you know the
the uh well I'm not talking about
Brilliance of the host I'm talking about
the guests you're going to have are PL
brilliant and there's going to be
moments in which you're seeing the uh
the quantity and I think the benefit of
many years of the security developer and
we've talked about that a few times also
allows for the perspective of trend
which I think will be fascinating I I
bet it would be super super interesting
to listen to some of our early episodes
maybe with a little bit of cringe about
ourselves on it but see what have been
the sort of the perspectives at the time
and listen to them two or three years
later and my my expectation would be is
our understanding will be like an order
of magnitude more evolved maybe two or
three months later we we'll we'll see
that's that's fair I don't know if we're
I don't know if we'll learn
[Laughter]
that but talking about what's next yeah
we got a few episodes coming up already
in fact the person that I'm speaking
speaking with next Amir shvat I know
someone you have gone back many years
with as well one of the things that
we're going to be talking about is
categorizing AI tooling so we what we
want to be able to do is say okay what
do we Deep dive in but we don't want to
just say let's Deep dive in AI what are
we Deep dive in and so we're going to be
categorizing the various AI tools
developer tools to understand what are
the aspects that developers or
organizations need to be thinking about
and understanding where they can apply
AI into their organizations into their
development organizations and then each
of those sections we're going to Deep
dive uh in those we've got Amir up next
who I'll be talking with and then we'll
Deep dive into our first topic which is
going to be around AI code completion
yeah and air will be brilliant on
categorizing those and Amir has done so
many things in Dev and Dev relations to
Dev movements including building out a
lot of that practice at switch and at
slack and now is an investor in really
smart AI Dev tools so I'm very keen to
hear that episode can't wait can't wait
excellent till next time thanks everyone
for tuning in guy it's a pleasure as
always yeah it's great to do this
opening show uh with you and I'm really
looking forward to to a whole horde of
amazing
[Applause]
conversations thanks for tuning in join
us next time on the AI native Dev
brought to you by Tesla
[Music]